smartmoney.com 2013-07-10

# Privacy Policy - MarketWatch

## The Wall Street Journal Digital Network and The Wall Street Journal, Barron's and SmartMoney Print Editions Privacy Policy

#### Effective October 18, 2011

### 1\. INTRODUCTION

Dow Jones & Company, Inc. ("Dow Jones," "us," or "we") (a) operates The Wall Street Journal Digital Network ("WSJDN"), comprised of The Wall Street Journal Online (home page at wsj.com), MarketWatch (home page at marketwatch.com and BigCharts.com), Barron's Online (home page at barrons.com), SmartMoney.com, AllThingsD.com, and FINS (home page at fins.com), including when these websites are accessed via the Internet, mobile or other device, and applications and sites affiliated with those products (collectively, the "Online Services"); and (b) publishes the print editions of The Wall Street Journal, Barron's, and SmartMoney. Dow Jones is part of the United States based operations of News Corporation.

Our Online Services are a network of general audience sites, are not targeted to children, and do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 14 years of age.

This Privacy Policy applies to: (a) consumers who provide us with information in connection with their subscriptions to U.S. print editions of The Wall Street Journal, Barron's and SmartMoney magazine; (b) all "users" of The Wall Street Journal Digital Network ("WSJDN"); and (c) users of any related services, applications or sites that link to this Privacy Policy. The Policy describes Dow Jones's collection and use of users' Personal Information (e.g., information that identifies a specific person, such as full name, postal address, telephone number, email address, or credit or debit card number) where that information is not otherwise publicly available on our Online Services. It also describes generally Dow Jones's practices for handling Other Information (e.g., interests, demographics and site usage) collected from you, through our Online Services, or from a third party to the extent such information is associated with a particular device, user or user account. By providing Personal Information to us, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

### 2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

#### **Personal Information**

"Personal Information" is the information that identifies you as an individual, such as name, postal address, telephone number, email address and credit or debit card number.

#### Personal Information You Submit

We collect Personal Information when you submit it to us, including but not limited to when you register for or subscribe to certain products or services, create a profile, participate in a sweepstakes or contest, take a survey, use an interactive feature (such as Email-to-a-Friend), or participate in a forum.

#### Personal Information We Receive from Third Parties

We may receive Personal Information about you from third parties, including, for example, information about your transactions, purchase history, or relationships with various product and service providers, and your use of certain applications. For example, if you access an Online Service through a third party connection or log-in, such as Facebook Connect, that third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to us. This information could include, but is not limited to, the user ID associated with your account, any information you have permitted the third party to share with us, and any information you have made public in connection with that service.

#### Other Information

"Other Information" is any information that does not reveal your specific identity, such as browser information, information collected through cookies and other technologies, demographic information, and aggregated information. We may combine Other Information with your Personal Information, and when we do, we treat the combined information as Personal Information.

#### Other Information You Submit

We collect Other Information when you submit it to us. It may include your gender, education, occupation, financial information (such as your income, investments, portfolio transactions and value, and other information), interests, photos, connections, and comments.

#### Other Information We Receive from Third Parties

We may receive Other Information about you from third parties, including, for example, demographic data, information about your interests, and information about your activities on other websites.

#### Other Information We Collect Automatically When You are Online

When you access our Online Services, we automatically collect certain information about those visits. For example, in order to permit your connection to our Online Services, our servers receive and record information about your computer and browser, potentially including your IP address, browser type, and other software or hardware information. If you access our Online Services from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier assigned to that device ("UDID") or other transactional information for that device in order to serve content to it. We also may use cookies and other tracking technologies (including browser cookies, pixels, beacons, and Adobe Flash technology including cookies), which are comprised of small bits of data that often include an anonymous unique identifier. Websites send this data to your browser when you first request a web page and then store the data on your computer so the website can access information when you make subsequent requests for pages from that site. We may use these technologies to facilitate our login processes; personalize your experience on WSJDN Services; display relevant content, products, services and advertising, as described further below; and collect and store information about your usage of our Online Services, such as pages you have visited, search queries you have run, and advertisements you have seen. We may also use cookies and similar tools to relate your use of our Online Services to Personal Information obtained from you or a reputable third party. For example, if you have asked us to provide you information about our upcoming products or promotions, cookie and/or clickstream data about your activities on our Online Services may allow us to limit the materials we provide you to items we think you will find interesting, based on your prior online activities and preferences.

Third parties that support our Online Services by serving advertisements or providing services, such as providing users with the ability to comment on content, allowing users to share content, or tracking aggregate site usage statistics, may also use these technologies to collect Other Information. Dow Jones may not control these third-party technologies and their use may be governed by the privacy policies of third parties using such technologies. For more information about third-party advertising on our Online Services, see the section on delivering advertising below.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but you can change your settings to notify you when a cookie is being set or updated, or to block cookies altogether. Please consult the "Help" section of your browser for more information (e.g., [http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies)](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies).

Users can manage the use of Flash technologies, including cookies, with the Flash management tools available at Adobe's website, see <http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security/privacy_policy/faq.html>. Please note that by blocking any or all cookies you may not have access to certain features or personalization available through our Online Services.

We may collect additional or different information from users of the WSJ Social Page, which is available at [https://social.wsj.com](https://social.wsj.com/). Our collection of information in connection with the WSJ Social Page is governed by a separate privacy policy, which is available at <http://online.wsj.com/public/page/wsjsocial_privacy_policy.html>.

### 3\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION 

We use the Personal Information we collect from and about you for the purposes set forth below. Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use and disclose it for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information.

To improve the quality of our products and services, we may combine the Personal and Other Information we collect with information that you provide to us in connection with your use of other Dow Jones products, services and websites, or information from third parties.

**To provide and manage our services**. We use the information we collect from and about you to provide our products and services and features to you, including: to process and fulfill your subscription, to send you information about your relationship or transactions with us, to measure and improve those services and features, to personalize your experience to allow you to comment on content, participate in online games, contests, promotions or rewards programs, to provide you with customer support, and to respond to inquiries. Some Online Services use the information we collect in site-specific ways. For example:

  * _FINS Resume Database_. FINS (fins.com) offers you the opportunity to create an online profile and store it in our database. When you create a profile on our system, you can choose one of the following options: (a) you can designate your profile as "Private" which means that your profile will not be shared with employers or recruiters unless you apply directly for a job, or (b) you can designate your profile as "Searchable" which means you allow your profile, including your name and contact information, to be searchable and viewable by employers or recruiters. IF YOU ELECT TO MAKE YOUR PROFILE SEARCHABLE, ALL INFORMATION (INCLUDING PERSONAL INFORMATION) THAT YOU INCLUDE IN YOUR PROFILE MAY BE VIEWED BY RECRUITERS AND EMPLOYERS. YOU SHOULD NOT ENTER ANY INFORMATION IN THE BODY OF YOUR PROFILE THAT YOU WISH TO REMAIN CONFIDENTIAL. We do not screen the credentials of employers or recruiters before allowing them to conduct searches in our database. Dow Jones is not responsible for the retention, use or privacy practices of that employer or recruiter after it has received your information. You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time. However, third parties who accessed the database or obtained a copy of your resume may have retained a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of resumes in these instances. 
  * _FINS Job Alerts_. FINS offers you the opportunity to sign up for job match alerts. These matches are generated by comparing a user's profile to our job database using our matching software. If you would like to review, change or delete your resume or job match alert, you can do so by signing in [here](http://www.fins.com/Finance/Candidate/CandidateDashboard.aspx) and following directions to edit.

**To deliver relevant content and recommendations**. To make your experience more interesting and personalized, we may use any of the Personal and Other Information we collect to assist us in delivering content on our Online Services. For example, if you use WSJ.com, we may use your WSJ.com reading history to personalize the content delivered to you on WSJ.com. This personalization feature is powered by a third party company called Gravity. If you would prefer not to see personalized content on WSJ.com by Gravity, please click [here](http://www.gravity.com/consumer) to opt-out with Gravity.

**To deliver relevant online advertising.** We may use any of the information we collect (in certain cases, such as with respect to financial information, only with your express permission) to assist us in delivering relevant ads to you when you visit our Online Services. (See Information We Collect, above, for details on the types of information we may use.) We may work with third party online advertising companies and advertisers who help deliver these ads to you. We will not sell, rent, or share your Personal Information with these third parties for such parties' own marketing purposes, unless you choose in advance to have your Personal Information shared for this purpose. Information about your activities on our Online Services and other non-personally identifiable information about you may be used to limit the online ads you encounter to those we believe are consistent with your interests. Third-party advertising networks and advertisers may also use cookies and similar technologies to collect and track non-personally identifiable information such as demographic information, aggregated information, and Internet activity to assist them in delivering advertising on our Online Services that is more relevant to your interests. Here are links to pages where you can manage the cookies set by some of the third parties that help us deliver online advertising:

  * [The Wall Street Journal Digital Network Registry, powered by BlueKai](http://www.marketwatch.com/support/privacy-preferences-registry)
  * <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>
  * <http://www.omniture.com/privacy/2o7>

To find out more about third-party online advertising and to opt out of this type of advertising, visit the [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

**To contact you**. Dow Jones may periodically send promotional materials or notifications related to our products and services to the email address you provided to us at registration or to your account. To help make these promotional materials more relevant to you, we may use and combine any of the Personal and Other Information we collect to assist us in sending you promotional materials. If you want to stop receiving promotional materials from us, you can change your setting through the appropriate link on the website account services page or follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. There are certain service notification emails that you may not opt-out of as long as you are registered with or subscribed to our products and services, such as renewal notices and notifications of changes to the our products and services or policies. We may also use your email address to respond to inquiries or requests you make to us.

We may make additional or different uses of information that is collected in connection with the WSJ Social Page, which is available at [https://social.wsj.com](https://social.wsj.com/). Our use of information that is collected in connection with the WSJ Social Page is governed by a separate privacy policy, which is available at <http://online.wsj.com/public/page/wsjsocial_privacy_policy.html>.

### 4\. HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

#### Information Made Public Through Use of Our Services and User Privacy Settings

Certain features on our Online Services give you an opportunity to interact with us and others. These may include forums, message boards, chats, submitting a letter to the editor, creating community profiles, and rating, tagging and commenting on articles. When you use these features, you should be aware that any information you submit, including your name, location and email address, may be publicly available to anyone, including other users, search engines, advertisers, third party application developers, and anyone else with access to our Online Services. We are not responsible for any information you choose to submit and make public through these interactive features.

#### Our Disclosure of Information

We only share your Personal Information with non-affiliated third parties when we believe sharing is permitted by you or authorized by this Privacy Policy. In addition, we may share your Personal Information with [Affiliated Companies](http://www.newscorp.com/). Dow Jones & Company, Inc. is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Information.

We also share your Personal Information:

**To manage corporate, third-party, and student subscriptions**. If your subscription is provided in whole or in part by your employer or other third party, we may notify the provider when you access or use your subscription. If you have a student subscription associated with a professor or school, we may notify your professor or school to confirm your subscription, access or use. When providing these notices, we may reveal limited amounts of your Personal Information such as your name or email address.

**To allow third-party service providers to assist us in providing and managing Our Services**. We may make your Personal Information available to certain third-party service providers, such as contractors, agents or sponsors, who help us manage or provide our products and services by, for example: developing or supporting products and features; sending email messages on our behalf; processing payments; fulfilling orders; delivering subscriptions; auditing; processing data or statistics; and serving, customizing or delivering marketing or ads. These outside service providers are required to protect Personal Information entrusted to them and not use it for any other purpose than the specific service they are providing to us. 

**To permit third parties to send you promotional materials**. If you subscribe to the U.S. edition of The Wall Street Journal, Barron's or SmartMoney print publications, we may share your contact information with other companies whose products and services may be of interest to you. While many of our subscribers appreciate receiving offerings from these companies, if you prefer that we do not share your information for this purpose, please contact the appropriate customer service center listed below in How to Access, Correct or Update Your Information. If you subscribe to Hulbert Financial Digest or Hulbert Financial Digest's related products Long Term Performance Ranking, Newsletter Honor Roll and Newsletter Profile (the "Hulbert Products"), Hulbert Financial Digest may provide the contact information of the Hulbert Products subscribers to third parties for marketing purposes. See below for contact information for Hulbert Financial Digest and more information on Hulbert's practices regarding sharing your information with third parties. If you sign up to receive a Special Offer on the MarketWatch.com Service, Dow Jones will forward your request along with your email and Special Offer delivery information, to the company making the relevant Special Offer so that it can contact you directly. Once your information is provided to another company pursuant to your request it is not governed by this Privacy Policy. 

If you subscribe solely to any other Online Service, we will not sell, rent, or share your Personal Information with third parties for such parties' own marketing purposes, unless you choose in advance to have your Personal Information shared for this purpose.

**To protect the rights of Dow Jones and our users**. There may be instances when Dow Jones may disclose your Personal Information, including situations where we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary in order to: (i) protect or defend the legal rights or property of Dow Jones, our Affiliated Companies or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (ii) protect the safety and security of users of the our products and services or members of the public; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; (iv) comply with the law or legal process, including laws outside your country of residence; or (v) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence.

**To complete a merger or sale of assets**. If Dow Jones sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of its assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, Dow Jones may transfer your information to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

We may make additional or different disclosures of information that is collected in connection with the WSJ Social Page, which is available at [https://social.wsj.com](https://social.wsj.com/). Our disclosure of information in connection with the WSJ Social Page is governed by a separate privacy policy, which is available at <http://online.wsj.com/public/page/wsjsocial_privacy_policy.html>.

### 5\. NOTICE

**Means of Notice and Choice**. This Privacy Policy is the primary means by which we provide you with notice and choice about our collection and use of your Personal Information. If we ask for specific Personal Information that will be used in a manner different from what is described in this Privacy Policy, we will inform you at the time of collection.

**Privacy Policy Changes**. Dow Jones may modify this Privacy Policy as necessary. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy that materially expand our rights to use your Personal Information, we will provide you with notice and choice consistent with applicable law.

**Cross-Border Transfer**. Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using our products and services, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than in your country.

**Data Retention**. We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

**Linked Websites**. Our Online Services may also be linked to sites operated by WSJDN affiliates (i.e., that are part of the News America Group: "[Affiliated Companies](http://www.newscorp.com/)") or third parties, and may carry advertisements or offer content, functionality, games or applications developed and maintained by third parties. Some of these third party sites may be co-branded with a Dow Jones logo, even though they are not operated or maintained by us. For example:

  * A portion of The Wall Street Journal Online Archive is hosted by an unrelated company - ProQuest - through its ProQuest Archiver service, and all article purchases are processed by ProQuest. ProQuest collects and uses your information in accordance with its privacy policy, and makes your information available to us. We will treat all information that ProQuest provides about you in accordance with this privacy policy.
  * The commenting tool for fins.com and allthingsd.com is provided by a third party online comment system called Disqus. Disqus is a third party application that allows visitors to post comments on fins.com and allthingsd.com and connect those and other comments across multiple websites. You may use your Disqus or certain select social media accounts to log-in and post comments on fins.com and allthingsd.com. When you log in and post a comment on these websites, Disqus may collect information about your visit to this and other Disqus partner sites, including information that you post and your IP address. If you register with and use Disqus, Disqus may collect and use additional information from and about you.

Dow Jones is not responsible for the privacy practices of any such third parties, and once you leave our Online Services via a link, enable a third-party service, or click an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third-party site. Additionally, although all Affiliated Companies adhere to the News Corporation corporate [Privacy Principles](http://www.newscorp.com/privacy.html), users who visit an Affiliated Company site should still refer to its separate privacy policy, which may differ in some respects from this Privacy Policy.

### 6\. SECURITY

Dow Jones uses commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard Personal Information in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification.

### 7\. HOW TO ACCESS, CORRECT OR UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION

You can access or modify your registration or subscription information and modify your preferences by contacting Customer Service for each of our publications, as indicated below. Most subscribers can also update their Personal Information online by signing on to their accounts and visiting the appropriate account management sections of our websites. Please note that if you have subscribed or registered for our print and online editions, or for more than one of our publications or services, you may need to update your information for each separately.

**The Wall Street Journal**  
You may contact The Wall Street Journal Customer Service at [wsj.service@dowjones.com](mailto:wsj.service@dowjones.com), 1-800-JOURNAL, or by visiting the [Help and Information Center](http://help.wsj.com/customer-service). Most subscribers to WSJ.com may also update their marketing preferences by going to the [Newsletters](http://setup2.wsj.com/pznsetup/sub/email/setup.html) page.

**Barron's**  
You may contact Barron's Customer Service at [barrons.service@dowjones.com](mailto:barrons.service@dowjones.com), 1-800-544-0422, or by visiting the [Contact Us/Help](http://online.barrons.com/contact) page. Most subscribers to Barrons.com may also update their marketing preferences by visiting the [Email Center](http://barrons.com/email).

**MarketWatch**  
You may contact Customer Service at [mwfeedback@marketwatch.com](mailto:mwfeedback@marketwatch.com). MarketWatch members also may update their account information by visiting [My Account](http://www.marketwatch.com/login/status.asp), and their marketing preferences by going to the [Communications Preferences](http://www.marketwatch.com/subscriptions/marketing.aspx) page.

**Hulbert Financial Digest Subscriptions**  
If you subscribe to _Hulbert Financial Digest_ or Hulbert Financial Digest's related products _Long Term Performance Ranking, Newsletter Honor Roll and Newsletter Profile_ (the "Hulbert Products"), your subscription information will be provided to, and managed directly by, Hulbert Financial Digest or its service providers. Hulbert Financial Digest provides the contact information of the Hulbert Products subscribers to third parties for marketing purposes. If you do not want your name and postal address provided to third parties for marketing purposes, you can opt out by contacting Hulbert Financial Digest by mail at P.O. Box 2025, Marion, OH 43306-4125 or by email at [orders@marketwatch.com](mailto:orders@marketwatch.com). You also can update your Hulbert Products subscription information by contacting Hulbert Financial Digest directly at the contacts above. These procedures are applicable even if you purchase your subscription to Hulbert Products through our Online Services.

**SmartMoney**  
You may contact SmartMoney Customer Service at [support@smartmoney.com](mailto:support@smartmoney.com). Registered users of SmartMoney.com may also correct or update their information by visiting the [Customer Service](http://www.smartmoney.com/customerservice/) section of SmartMoney.com. Subscribers of SmartMoney Magazine may correct or update their information by clicking [here](http://service.smartmoney.com/).

**AllThingsD**  
You may contact AllThingsD Customer Service at [help@allthingsd.com](mailto:help@allthingsd.com). Registered users of AllThingsD.com may also update their information and email preferences by clicking [here](http://allthingsd.com/wp-admin/profile.php).

**FINS**  
You may contact FINS Customer Service at [support@fins.com](mailto:support@fins.com) or 1-877-FINS-450. Most registered members of FINS may also update their account information and marketing preferences by visiting [My Account](http://www.fins.com/Finance/Candidate/CandidateDashboard.aspx) .

Your California Privacy Rights

California Law permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please write to us at:

Dow Jones & Company  
Attn: DM Disclosure Manager   
200 Burnett Road  
Chicopee, MA 01020

and include your name and the address to which you would like us to respond.

### 8\. CONTACT US

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacypolicy@dowjones.com](mailto:privacypolicy@dowjones.com).
